Heine, Heinrich, 1797-1856. Letters to Mathilde Heine (MS Ger 108.14): Guide.
Letters to Mathilde Heine,
1844.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Ger 108.14
Heine, Heinrich, 1797-1856.
1 v. (.1 linear ft.)
Letters from German poet Heinrich Heine to his wife Mathilde (Mirat) Heine chiefly concerning his health.
*66M-151
Gift of John L. Loeb, 730 Park Avenue, New York, New York 10021; received: 1967 May 2.
Sold by Mathilde Heine in 1869 to Julius Campe. Sold by the Campe family after 1930 to Madame Alexandrine de Rothschild, the previous owner.
Heine was a Jewish-German poet, who married Mathilde Heine (Crescence Eugénie Mirat) in 1841.
Arranged chronologically.
Includes 11 letters from Heine, who was visiting family in Hamburg, to Mathilde Heine in Paris, chiefly concerning his health. Nos. 1-3, 5-7, 9 11 publ. in German, nos. 4 10 publ. in French, see Briefe... ed. Friedrich Hirth (1950). Vol. II, nos. 800, 801, 802, 803, 805, 806, 807, 809, 815, 817, 818.
- Heine, Heinrich, 1797-1856. 11 A.L.s. to Mathilde (Mirat) Heine; 1844.
  - Hamburg, 12 Aug 1844., (1); 1s.(3p.)
  - [Same, 16 Aug 1844]., (2); 1s.(3p.)
  - same, 20 Aug 1844., (3); 1s.(2p.)
  - same, 23 Aug 1844., (4); 1s.(2p.)
  - same, 27 Aug 1844., (5); 1s.(3p.)
  - same, 30 Aug 1844., (6); 1s.(3p.)
  - same, 2 Sep 1844., (7); 1s.(4p.)
  - same, 4 Sep 1844., (8); 1s.(2p.)
    Apparently written on 4 Oct.
  - same, 11 Sep 1844., (9); 1s.(4p.)
  - same, 25 Sep 1844., (10); 1s.(2p.)
  - same, 1 Oct 1844., (11); 1s.(3p.)